[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the name of the protagonist in 'The Hunger Games' series?",
    "options": ["Katniss Everdeen", "Peeta Mellark", "Gale Hawthorne", "Primrose Everdeen"],
    "correct_option": "Katniss Everdeen"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "In which district does Katniss Everdeen reside at the beginning of 'The Hunger Games'?",
    "options": ["District 12", "District 8", "District 4", "District 13"],
    "correct_option": "District 12"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What is the name of the deadly event where tributes fight to the death in 'The Hunger Games'?",
    "options": ["The Reaping", "The Feast", "The Duel", "The Arena"],
    "correct_option": "The Arena"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Who is the President of Panem in 'The Hunger Games' series?",
    "options": ["President Snow", "President Alma Coin", "President Paylor", "President Coriolanus Snow"],
    "correct_option": "President Snow"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "What is the name of the fiery dress designed for Katniss during the Tribute Parade in 'Catching Fire'?",
    "options": ["Flame Gown", "Fire Dress", "Mockingjay Attire", "Girl on Fire Outfit"],
    "correct_option": "Girl on Fire Outfit"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which character sacrifices themselves for Katniss in the first Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Peeta Mellark", "Gale Hawthorne", "Primrose Everdeen", "Rue"],
    "correct_option": "Rue"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "What is the name of the rebellion formed against the Capitol in 'Mockingjay'?",
    "options": ["The Uprising", "The Resistance", "The Revolution", "The Rebellion"],
    "correct_option": "The Rebellion"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the symbol of the rebellion in 'The Hunger Games' series?",
    "options": ["The Mockingjay", "The Rose", "The Arrow", "The Sun"],
    "correct_option": "The Mockingjay"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Who is the Head Gamemaker in 'The Hunger Games'?",
    "options": ["Seneca Crane", "Plutarch Heavensbee", "Cinna", "Fulvia Cardew"],
    "correct_option": "Seneca Crane"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "What is the deadly event introduced in 'Catching Fire' where past victors must compete again?",
    "options": ["Quarter Quell", "Tribute Twist", "Victor's Vendetta", "Reaping Redux"],
    "correct_option": "Quarter Quell"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is the name of the luxury train that transports tributes to the Capitol in 'The Hunger Games'?",
    "options": ["Capitol Express", "Victor's Voyage", "Luxury Liner", "Hogwarts Express"],
    "correct_option": "Capitol Express"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "In 'Mockingjay,' what is the purpose of the mission called the 'Star Squad'?",
    "options": ["Rescue Peeta", "Capture President Snow", "Retrieve Mockingjay Propo", "Assassinate President Coin"],
    "correct_option": "Assassinate President Coin"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Who is the mentor and stylist for Katniss Everdeen in 'The Hunger Games'?",
    "options": ["Cinna", "Effie Trinket", "Haymitch Abernathy", "Portia"],
    "correct_option": "Cinna"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What is the name of the gamekeeper who assists Katniss in the Arena during the 75th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Beetee Latier", "Plutarch Heavensbee", "Wiress", "Mags"],
    "correct_option": "Beetee Latier"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What is the Capitol's punishment for District 12 after Katniss and Peeta's victory in the 74th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Increased Rations", "Annexation", "Mining Ban", "Quarter Quell"],
    "correct_option": "Quarter Quell"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "What is the name of the game where tributes must stay alive in a constantly changing environment?",
    "options": ["The Maze", "The Clockwork Arena", "The Jungle Hunt", "The Hunger Games"],
    "correct_option": "The Clockwork Arena"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Who becomes the new President of Panem after the fall of President Snow?",
    "options": ["Katniss Everdeen", "Alma Coin", "Peeta Mellark", "Gale Hawthorne"],
    "correct_option": "Alma Coin"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What is the name of the district that specializes in luxury goods and is known for its elaborate parties?",
    "options": ["District 1", "District 4", "District 5", "District 12"],
    "correct_option": "District 1"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "In 'Catching Fire,' what is the name of the poisonous fog that poses a threat to the tributes?",
    "options": ["Tracker Jackers", "Acid Rain", "Blood Rain", "Fog of Death"],
    "correct_option": "Fog of Death"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What is the nickname given to Katniss and Peeta's alliance during the 74th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["The Star-Crossed Allies", "The Mockingjay Duo", "The Dynamic Duo", "The Lovebirds"],
    "correct_option": "The Star-Crossed Allies"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "What is the name of the rebellion's symbol that becomes synonymous with the fight against the Capitol?",
    "options": ["The Arrow", "The Rose", "The Mockingjay", "The Rebel Star"],
    "correct_option": "The Mockingjay"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Which tribute from District 11 sacrifices himself in protest after Rue's death in the 74th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Thresh", "Cato", "Marvel", "Glimmer"],
    "correct_option": "Thresh"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "What is the name of the deadly gas used by the Capitol in the 75th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Sleeping Gas", "Venom Gas", "Tracker Gas", "Poison Gas"],
    "correct_option": "Tracker Gas"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "Who is the stylist for Peeta Mellark during the 74th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Cinna", "Effie Trinket", "Portia", "Flavius"],
    "correct_option": "Portia"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "In 'Mockingjay: Part 1,' what is the primary objective of the rebels' mission in the Capitol?",
    "options": ["Rescue Peeta", "Assassinate President Snow", "Retrieve Prim", "Destroy the Hunger Games Arena"],
    "correct_option": "Rescue Peeta"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the name of the deadly muttations encountered by the tributes in the Arena?",
    "options": ["Wolf Mutts", "Tracker Jackers", "Mutt Cheetahs", "Mutant Bees"],
    "correct_option": "Wolf Mutts"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Which character is known for saying, 'May the odds be ever in your favor'?",
    "options": ["President Snow", "Effie Trinket", "Haymitch Abernathy", "Caesar Flickerman"],
    "correct_option": "Effie Trinket"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "What is the name of the addictive substance that Gale Hawthorne and others illegally hunt in District 12?",
    "options": ["Moonshine", "Opium", "White Rain", "Mockingjay Poison"],
    "correct_option": "White Rain"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "Who plays the character Finnick Odair, a former tribute from District 4, in 'Catching Fire'?",
    "options": ["Sam Claflin", "Liam Hemsworth", "Josh Hutcherson", "Alexander Ludwig"],
    "correct_option": "Sam Claflin"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "In 'Mockingjay: Part 2,' what is the name of the deadly obstacle course set by the Capitol in the sewers?",
    "options": ["The Maze of Despair", "The Labyrinth of Doom", "The Tunnel Trials", "The Pod Maze"],
    "correct_option": "The Pod Maze"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What is the name of the gamekeeper who helps Katniss and Peeta during the 74th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Cinna", "Plutarch Heavensbee", "Haymitch Abernathy", "Seneca Crane"],
    "correct_option": "Haymitch Abernathy"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "What is the nickname given to the genetically modified animals used by the Capitol in the Arena?",
    "options": ["Mutations", "Muttations", "Capitol Beasts", "Genetic Hybrids"],
    "correct_option": "Muttations"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "What is the name of the event where tributes are interviewed by Caesar Flickerman before the Hunger Games begin?",
    "options": ["The Reaping Show", "The Tribute Talk", "The Pre-Games Interview", "The Capitol Chat"],
    "correct_option": "The Pre-Games Interview"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "Who is the Head Gamemaker responsible for creating the Arena in 'Catching Fire'?",
    "options": ["Seneca Crane", "Plutarch Heavensbee", "Caesar Flickerman", "Octavia"],
    "correct_option": "Plutarch Heavensbee"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "In 'Mockingjay: Part 1,' what is the name of the television program hosted by Caesar Flickerman?",
    "options": ["The Capitol Show", "Flickerman's Fables", "The Caesar Chronicles", "Capitol TV"],
    "correct_option": "Capitol TV"
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "What is the name of the mysterious district that plays a significant role in the rebellion?",
    "options": ["District 13", "District 11", "District 8", "District X"],
    "correct_option": "District 13"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Which character is known for saying, 'Remember, girl on fire, I'm still betting on you'?",
    "options": ["Gale Hawthorne", "Peeta Mellark", "Cinna", "Haymitch Abernathy"],
    "correct_option": "Cinna"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "What is the primary industry of District 11, where Rue and Thresh originate?",
    "options": ["Fishing", "Mining", "Agriculture", "Manufacturing"],
    "correct_option": "Agriculture"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "Who is the victor of the 65th Hunger Games and becomes a mentor for Katniss and Peeta?",
    "options": ["Haymitch Abernathy", "Mags", "Johanna Mason", "Finnick Odair"],
    "correct_option": "Haymitch Abernathy"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "What is the name of the poisonous berries that Katniss and Peeta use to defy the Capitol in the 74th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Nightlock", "Shadowberries", "Venomberries", "Capitolbane"],
    "correct_option": "Nightlock"
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "What is the significance of the Mockingjay pin that Katniss wears throughout the series?",
    "options": ["Gift from Peeta", "Family Heirloom", "Rebellion Symbol", "Good Luck Charm"],
    "correct_option": "Rebellion Symbol"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "In 'Catching Fire,' what is the special rule announced for the 75th Hunger Games, known as the Quarter Quell?",
    "options": ["Tribute Alliances Forbidden", "No Weapons Allowed", "Double the Tributes", "Night Games Only"],
    "correct_option": "Double the Tributes"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Who is Katniss's primary stylist for the Victory Tour and the 75th Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Cinna", "Portia", "Effie Trinket", "Flavius"],
    "correct_option": "Cinna"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "What is the name of the training center where tributes prepare for the Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["Capitol Center", "Victor's Village", "Cornucopia Complex", "Training Grounds"],
    "correct_option": "Training Grounds"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "What is the fate of Cinna, Katniss's stylist, in 'Catching Fire'?",
    "options": ["Victor of the Games", "Captured by the Capitol", "Rebel Leader", "Public Execution"],
    "correct_option": "Public Execution"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "What is the name of the weapon specialist who trains Katniss and Peeta for the Quarter Quell?",
    "options": ["Beetee Latier", "Johanna Mason", "Enobaria", "Brutus"],
    "correct_option": "Johanna Mason"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "What is the title of the propaganda film created to inspire rebellion in 'Mockingjay: Part 1'?",
    "options": ["The Mockingjay Chronicles", "District Heroes", "The Rebel Diaries", "Mockingjay Propo"],
    "correct_option": "Mockingjay Propo"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Who plays the character President Alma Coin, the leader of the rebellion, in 'Mockingjay'?",
    "options": ["Julianne Moore", "Cate Blanchett", "Tilda Swinton", "Meryl Streep"],
    "correct_option": "Julianne Moore"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "What is the name of the technology used by the Capitol to manipulate the appearance of the Arena in the Hunger Games?",
    "options": ["HoloVision", "Reality Distorter", "Tracker Jackers", "Holographic Terrain"],
    "correct_option": "Holographic Terrain"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "What does the term \"The Hanging Tree\" refer to in 'Mockingjay: Part 1'?",
    "options": ["A secret meeting place", "A lethal trap", "A famous landmark", "A rebellion song"],
    "correct_option": "A rebellion song"
  }
]